RAMER PAILOU B. NUÑEZA | Software Developer

Location: Cebu City, Philippines Telephone: 09086345307 Email: pailou.nuneza@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pailoununeza

Professional Profile

A dedicated professional with 5 years experience in the software industry specializing in web development from ground up to production support. I am willing to learn any new technologies and will do my best to contribute my skills and experience to your development team.

Technical Skills

- C# ASP.NET / CORE
- PHP Laravel
- JavaScript (Node,Express)
- Azure DevOps Server/TFS
- Understand OOP

- Version Control (Git)
- Visual Studio/Code
- SQL & MySQL
- Angular & Vue
- Unit Test (TestLink)

- Vuetify
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Figma Prototyper
- Heroku

Career Summary

Digital Excellence Group

June 2020 - Current

Role: Software Developer

Outline:

Web application support, add features to the application and also fix issues that occur in production.

Key Responsibilities:

- Add enhancements based on client's request and also fixing existing bugs.
- Deploy new features and fixes in production using DeployHQ
- Collaborate with the team during task planning
- Create test scripts using testcafe

Alliance Software Inc.

October 2019 - June 2020

Software Development Engineer II

Role: Production Support

Outline:

Support HRIS web app on production environment. Investigate, document, implement fixes for any issue may occur.

Key Responsibilities:

- Add enhancements based on client's request and also fixing existing bugs.
- Responsible in any bugs/issues in production environment
- Verify the issue using the team foundation server (TFS) as project management tool.
- Involve in communicating with the client for task verifications or concerns
- Analyze the issue, create root cause analysis (RCA) document and proof of testing (POT) when investigating the bug.
- Creates a function list for the enhancements and estimates the specs for timeline schedule.
- Implements long term fix as much as possible

Alliance Software Inc.

November 2018 - October 2019

Software Development Engineer II

Role: Developer

Outline:

Involved in HRIS web app project from design, development, testing and deployment.

Key Responsibilities:

- Creates a function list for the enhancements and estimates the specs for timeline schedule.
- Creates high level design (HLD) and low level design (LLD) documents when creating a new enhancements
- Creates test cases and steps for Unit Testing using TestLink.
- Verify the issue using the team foundation server (TFS) as project management tool.
- Took part in analyzing software requirements and created detailed design specifications.

M. Lhuillier Financial Services, Inc

September 2015 - November 2018

Role: Software Programmer

Outline:

Developed and supported company projects from ground up to production.

Key Responsibilities

- Developed a web project that helps the branches of the company to request office items online.
- Responsible for supporting and maintaining the application after its been deployed to the production server.
- Took part in analyzing software requirements and created detailed design specifications.
- Developed a web app that monitors QA testers progress.
- Involved in a CRM team and developed web application for customer survey

OJT at Rural Bank of Catmon, Cebu

April 2014 - March 2015

Role: IT Staff Assistant - OJT

Outline

Worked as on-the-job trainee, assisting any computer issues and paperworks.

Key Responsibilities:

- Assist in computer related issues in the office.
- Work as assistant teller in Pantawid Pamilyang Pilipino Program (4Ps)
- Create a simple application to help the loans department.

Education

- BSIT Cebu Technological University Carmen Campus (2015)
- BSIT Saint Paul College Foundation Mandaue (2011)
- Gabriel Jurado Foundation School (2010)

Character Reference

Glorife Nosido

Software Developer at Knowles Electronics Phils.

Contact: 09054166901 Email: iamgeenose@gmail.com

Jamillo Joe Bagotsay

QA Specialist at Alliance Software Inc.

Contact: 09565887211

Email: jambagotsay@gmail.com

Ruby Hortelano

Software Developer at Fujitsu Philippines

Contact: 09205263157

Email: rub.hortelano@gmail.com